Amitesh Pandey

Having around 6 years of experience in large scale software development using C++ on best utilization of the Data Structures, OOPs with excellent problem-solving skills, ability to perform well in team and passionate about coding as well. So far worked on products ranging from Test&Measurement, PLM and Telecommunication domains.



amitesh13.pandey@gmail.com



+917899374480



Bengaluru, India



in linkedin.com/in/amitesh13

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Specialist

Nokia

08/2022 - Present

Bangaluru

Bangaluru

5G:

- Platform: Linux, C++.
- Development Tools: VS Code, Mobaxterm, Gerrit, JIRA, Jenkins, Python (Programming Language).
- Description: It is a new global wireless standard after 1G, 2G, 3G, and 4G networks. 5G enables a new kind of network that is designed to connect virtually everyone and everything together including machines, objects, and devices such as e-health, connected vehicles and traffic systems and advanced mobile cloud gaming have arrived.
- Role: Developing new feature and fixing the bug in L3 layer and L3 proxy, corresponding to that maintaining and writing Unit test, SCT, Sanity

R&D Software Engineering Specialist

Dassault Systèmes

07/2019 - 07/2022 Bangaluru

3DEXCITE DELTAGEN:

- Platform: Windows, C++, Qt.
- Development Tools: Visual studio, Git, JIRA, Jenkins.
- Description: This is a powerful automated, 3D visualization pipeline that enhances design, engineering, and marketing in real-time. Rapid virtual prototyping accelerates product design and generates premium marketing content for nearly any campaign scenario: offline, online, and immersive.
- Role: C++/QT Developer, Analysis and Unit testing

Software Design Engineer

Tektronix (India) Private Limited

06/2018 - 07/2019

Digital Power Management Analysis:

- Platform: Windows, C++, QML.
- Development Tools: Visual studio, Git, JIRA, Jenkins.
- Hardware used: Tektronix Mso4,5,6 Series (Multiplatform- Windows and Linux).
- Description: Automated software solution for analysis of power rail voltages and currents (transient and steady state) on oscilloscopes. Testing of digital power boards which have multiple voltage levels is done using this solution. Measurements like ripple, overshoot and undershoot, turn on time and turn off time are classical in this solution.
- Role: C++/QML Developer, Analysis and Unit testing

SKILLS



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science Oriental Institute of Science & Technology (RGPV)

08/2012 - 06/2016 Bhopal, India

12th

Govt. Venkat H. S. Excellence School no.1

07/2010 - 04/2011 Satna(M.P.), India

10th

Govt. Venkat H. S. Excellence School no.1

07/2008 - 04/2009

Satna(M.P.), India

CERTIFICATES

C++ Essential Training(09/2022 - 10/2022

R&D C++ Developer (08/2019 - 11/2019) Dassault Système

COMPUTER NETWORKING (01/2015 - 06/2015) Basic working and understanding of networking software and application.

COMPUTER APLLICATION (08/2007 - 09/2008) Familiarization with the windows software and basic structure of programming